A Guide to the Hao Wang papers, Rockefeller University Faculty FA274
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Manuscripts, Notes, and Notebooks, 3
  - Unfoldered Notes and Manuscripts, Includes: “A Problem of Algebraic Manipulation” “Work Done on NSF Grants” “Selected Works in Logic, by Thoralf Skolem, edited by Jens Erik Fenstad” (Box 142, Folder 1730)
  - Unfoldered Notes and Manuscripts, Includes: “Philosophy through Mathematics and Logic” (Box 143, Folder 1731)
  - Unfoldered Notes and Materials (Box 143, Folder 1732)
  - Unfoldered Notes, Brouwer (Box 143, Folder 1733)
  - Unfoldered Notes, Correspondence, and Manuscripts, Includes: “Interview mit Professor Hempel” (by Köhler), 1986 “The Concept of Set” “Lecture on Rotating Universes” “Introductory Notes to *1949b” “Textual Notes for *1949b” “The Replacement of Time” by Steven F. Savitt “Deduction and Implication” (Box 143, Folder 1734)
  - Unfoldered Portion of Manuscript, Pages 23-25 (Box 143, Folder 1735)
  - Unfoldered Publications, Includes: “Preliminary Examination for Philosophy, Politics, and Economics, Hilary Term 1961” “Harvard University Division of Engineering and Applied Physics, Doctors of Philosophy, 1947-1965” “International Congress of Mathematicians 1954, Scientific Program” “Outline of the History of Mathematics” by Raymond Clare Archibald “The British Academy Yearbook 1977-8” “The Institute for Advanced Study, Bulletin No. 12, 1945-1946” “Boston Arts Festival, 1962 Program” “Universities’ China Committee in London, Annual Report, 1960-61” “Mechanical Mathematics and Inferential Analysis” by Hao Wang “Hiroshima Mon Destine: A Collection of a Play and Two Essays on Hiroshima and Nuclear War” by Kai Hong (Box 143, Folder 1736)
  - Unfoldered Reprints, Includes: “Comments on Ludwig Wittgenstein’s Remarks on the Foundations of Mathematics” by Paul Bernays “Philosophical Investigations by Ludwig Wittgenstein, Review by P.F. Strawson “Ludwig Wittgenstein” by Gilbert Ryle “Linguistic Structure and the Structure of Experience” by Erik Stenius “Betrachtungen zu Ludwig Wittgensteins ‘Bemerkungen über die Grundlagen der Mathematik’” by Paul Bernays “The Analytic and the Nonempirical” by J.M.E. Moravcsik “Wittgenstein’s Theory and Practice of Philosophy” by G. Kreisel “Wittgenstein on Some Questions in Foundations of Mathematics” by Alice Ambrose “Religious ‘Seeing-As’” by William L. Reese (Box 143, Folder 1737)
  - Unlabeled Correspondence, Manuscripts, and Notes, Includes: “Operational Origins of Mathematical Objects and the Quandary of Reification – The Case of Function” by Anna Sfard “Alfred Renyi” “Philosophy of Mathematics in China” by Yuxin Zheng “On the Dual Nature of Mathematical Conceptions: Reflections on Processes and Objects as Different Sides of the Same Coin” by Anna Sfard “Inner Vision, Outer Truth” by Reuben Hersh “Charles E. Morgan’s Electro-Physiology and Therapeutics: An Unknown English Version of du Bois-Reymond’s Thierische Elektricität” by Paul F. Cranefield “Toward a Semiotics of Mathematics” by Brian Rotman “Rene Descartes, 1596-1650” “An Argument Against the Plausibility of Church’s Thesis” by László Kalmár “The Philosophy of Mathematics, Historically Reviewed” “Object and Process” “Baruch Spinoza, 1632-1677” “The Crisis in Foundations,” 1993 “Gottlob Frege, 1848-1925” “Locke-Berkeley-Hume” “Gottfried Wilhelm Freiherr von Leibniz, 1646-1716” (Box 143, Folder 1738)
  - Unlabeled Folder, Includes: “Wittgenstein’s Philosophies of Mathematics” by Steve Gerrard “Tautology: How Not to Use a Word” by Burton Dreben and Juliet Floyd “Metaphysics in the Vienna Circle” by Eckehart Köhler “Wittgenstein on Meaning, Understanding, and Community” by Barry Stroud “Quine on Exile and Acquiescence” by Barry Stroud “Meaning, Understanding, and Translation” by Barry Stroud (Box 144, Folder 1739)
  - Unlabeled Folder, Includes: “Tautology: How Not to Use a Word” by Burton Dreben and Juliet Floyd “Tharp and Conceptual Logic” “Wittgenstein on 2, 2, 2…: The Opening of Remarks on the Foundations of Mathematics” by Juliet Floyd (Box 144, Folder 1740)
  - Unlabeled Folder (Box 144, Folder 1741)
  - Unlabeled Folder (Box 144, Folder 1742)
  - Unlabeled Folder (Box 144, Folder 1743)
  - Unlabeled Folder, Includes: “Remarks on Machines, Sets, and the Decision Problems” “Games, Logic and Computers” (Box 144, Folder 1744)
  - Unlabeled Folder, Includes: “Book Review: Patricia S. Churchland and Terrence J. Sejnowski, The Computational Brain” by George N. Reeke, Jr. “Gödel and Physical Theory” by Wolfgang Yourgrau “Western Philosophy and China at Turning Point of Centuries” by Yao Jiehou “Book Review, Marvin Minsky, The Society of Mind” by George N. Reeke, Jr. (Box 144, Folder 1745)
  - Unlabeled Folder, Includes: “Mathematical Truth” by Paul Benacerraf “The Golden Bull” by Bradford Dunham (Box 144, Folder 1746)
  - Unlabeled Folder, 1957 (Box 144, Folder 1747)
  - Unlabeled Folder, 1961; Includes: “Eighty Years of Foundational Studies” (Box 144, Folder 1748)
  - Unlabeled Folder, Manuscripts and Notes on Gödel (Box 144, Folder 1749)
  - Unlabeled Folder, Manuscripts, Introduction and Chapter III, "From Mathematics to Philosophy (Box 144, Folder 1750)
  - Unlabeled Folder, Material on Skolem, Correspondents include: Wang, Fenstad, Gödel, Aubert (Box 145, Folder 1751)
  - Unlabeled Folder, Revisions, Chapter X of "From Mathematics to Philosophy" (Box 145, Folder 1752)
  - Unlabeled Gödel-related Chapters (Box 145, Folder 1753)
  - Unlabeled Gödel-related Manuscript (Box 145, Folder 1754)
  - Unlabeled Manuscript, Pages I-1 to III-3 37 (Box 145, Folder 1755)
  - Unlabeled Manuscript, Pages 7-56 (Box 145, Folder 1756)
  - Unlabeled Manuscripts (Box 145, Folder 1757)
  - Unlabeled Manuscripts (Box 145, Folder 1758)
  - Unlabeled Manuscripts, Includes: “Basic Ambiguity of ‘Information Processing Systems’”/“Minds and Computers” “Mind, Machine and Mathematics” (Box 145, Folder 1759)
  - Unlabeled Manuscripts (Box 145, Folder 1760)
  - Unlabeled Manuscripts, Includes: “Tharp and Conceptual Logic” “Philosophy of Sex, Final Assignment” (Box 145, Folder 1761)
  - Unlabeled Manuscripts, Includes: “Frege and Husserl on Number” by Richard Tieszen “Mathematical Intuition and Husserl’s Phenomenology” by Richard Tieszen “What is a Proof?” by Richard Tieszen “Husserl and the Philosophy of Mathematics” “Kurt Gödel and Phenomenology” by Richard Tieszen (Box 145, Folder 1762)
  - Unlabeled Manuscripts, Includes: “On Formalization” “Elementary Logic” (Box 146, Folder 1763)
  - Unlabeled Manuscripts, Includes: “Philosophy as Gödel Saw It” “The Joys of Independence: Some Uses of Logic” “The Complexities of Completeness” “Who’s Afraid of Alfred Tarski? Truth-Definitions for IF First-Order Languages” “The Functions of Logic and the Problem of Truth-Definition” “The Game of Logic” “Frege’s Fallacy Foiled: Independence-Friendly Logic” (Box 146, Folder 1764)
  - Unlabeled Manuscripts, "Logic and Foundations" and "The Unity of Knowledge", 1966-1968 (Box 146, Folder 1765)
  - Unlabeled Manuscripts and Notes (Box 146, Folder 1766)
  - Unlabeled Manuscripts and Notes (Box 146, Folder 1767)
  - Unlabeled Manuscripts and Notes (Box 146, Folder 1768)
  - Unlabeled Manuscripts and Notes, Includes: “To Will Only Perspicuity” “Is the Brain a Digital Computer?” by John R. Searle “Preface, LCG” “An Unsolvable Problem of Elementary Number Theory” by Alonzo Church (Box 146, Folder 1769)
  - Unlabeled Manuscripts and Notes (Box 146, Folder 1770)
  - Unlabeled Manuscripts and Notes, Includes: “An Interpretation of Piaget” “China’s Continuing Revolution” (Box 146, Folder 1771)
  - Unlabeled Manuscripts and Notes, Includes: “Conversations with Kurt Gödel” “A Finitary Proof of the Consistency of N and PA in a Formal System (Parts I and II)” by Shih-Chao Liu “Two Theorems Concerning the Axiom ⇁p →(p→q)” by Shih-Chao Liu (Box 147, Folder 1772)
  - Unlabeled Manuscripts and Notes (Box 147, Folder 1773)
  - Unlabeled Manuscripts and Notes, Includes: “Aperiodicity and Constraints” “Book Review, ‘Paradigms Lost: Images of Man in the Mirror of Science’ by Eckehard Köhler” (Box 147, Folder 1774)
  - Unlabeled Manuscripts and Notes, Includes: “Wittgenstein’s and Other Mathematical Philosophies” “Gödel and Wittgenstein” (Box 147, Folder 1775)
  - Unlabeled Manuscripts and Notes, Includes: “Discussions with Kurt Gödel” “Notes and Comments on ‘Philosophy and Anti-Philosophy,’ First part of Dreams of Reason, H. Pagels” “Response to Hao Wang’s Comments/Draft of Part I, The Dreams of Reason” (Box 147, Folder 1776)
  - Unlabeled Manuscripts and Notes, Includes: “Computability and Tiling Problems (outline only)” “Comments on the Penrose Tiles – September 1975” by Raphael M. Robinson “On the Theorem of Henry Blumberg” by Casper Goffman “The Independence Proofs of Scott” “The Gödel Theory” by Tharp (Box 147, Folder 1777)
  - Unlabeled Manuscripts and Notes, Includes: “Philosophy through Mathematics and Logic” (Box 147, Folder 1778)
  - Unlabeled Manuscripts and Notes (Box 147, Folder 1779)
  - Unlabeled Manuscripts and Notes, 1950s (Box 147, Folder 1780)
  - Unlabeled Manuscripts, Chapters 11, 12, 13 (Box 147, Folder 1781)
  - Unlabeled Manuscripts, Chapter 12 (Box 147, Folder 1782)
  - Unlabeled Manuscripts, Chapter 12 (Box 147, Folder 1783)
  - Unlabeled Manuscripts, Chapter 14 (Box 147, Folder 1784)
  - Unlabeled Notebook, Includes: “Knowledge and Logic – Introduction” “Mathematical Logic and Philosophy of Mathematics” “Characterization of Some General Mathematical Concepts” “Russell’s Logic and Some General Issues” (Box 148, Folder 1785)
  - Unlabeled Notebook, Includes: “Mathematical Logic and Philosophy of Mathematics” “Characterization of Some General Mathematical Concepts” “Knowledge and Logic – Introduction” “Relevance and Forms of Life (Box 148, Folder 1786)
  - Unlabeled Notebook (Box 148, Folder 1787)
  - Unlabeled Notebook, 1948 (Box 148, Folder 1788)
  - Unlabeled Notebook and Notes (Box 148, Folder 1789)
  - Unlabeled Notebook, Hao Wang (Box 148, Folder 1790)
  - Unlabeled Notebooks (Box 148, Folder 1791)
  - Unlabeled Notes (Box 149, Folder 1792)
  - Unlabeled Notes (Box 149, Folder 1793)
  - Unlabeled Notes (Box 149, Folder 1794)
  - Unlabeled Notes (Box 149, Folder 1795)
  - Unlabeled Notes (Box 149, Folder 1796)
  - Unlabeled Notes (Box 149, Folder 1797)
  - Unlabeled Notes, Includes: “Large Sets” “Sets and Concepts” “Notes on Sets and Concepts” “Objectivism of Sets and Concepts” (Box 149, Folder 1798)
  - Unlabeled Notes (Box 149, Folder 1799)
  - Unlabeled Notes (Box 149, Folder 1800)
  - Unlabeled Notes, Includes: “Notes on the Conversations” [Gödel-related] (Box 149, Folder 1801)
  - Unlabeled Notes, Includes: “The Nature and Place of Philosophy” “Logical Truth and Analyticity” “Responding to Russell and Carnap” “Harvard and C.I. Lewis” “Quine’s Logical Ideas and Philosophical Presuppositions in Historical Perspective” “Philosophical Presuppositions” “From Vienna 1932 to America 1981” “Interactions with Students” “Thinking about China: Facts and Questions” “China’s Transition to Socialism” “To Each According to His Work” “China and Transitional Phases After Revolution” (Box 149, Folder 1802)
  - Unlabeled Notes (Box 149, Folder 1803)
  - Unlabeled Notes, Includes: “Alternative Philosophies as Complementary” “Alternative Philosophies” (Box 150, Folder 1804)
  - Unlabeled Notes (Box 150, Folder 1805)
  - Unlabeled Notes (Box 150, Folder 1806)
  - Unlabeled Notes (Box 150, Folder 1807)
  - Unlabeled Notes, Includes: “Philosophical Fragments” “Logic, Computation and Philosophy” “Logic and Foundations” (Box 150, Folder 1808)
  - Unlabeled Notes, Includes: “Math. 287 Lecture Notes, Spring 1967” “Forcing à la Solovay” by Jack Silver (Box 150, Folder 1809)
  - Unlabeled Notes, Includes: “On the Decision Problem of the First Order Predicate Calculus: The Classical Cases and Solvable Surányi Subcases” by B. Dreben and R. Goldberg “Decidability of Gödel’s Case with Equality” (Box 150, Folder 1810)
  - Unlabeled Notes (Box 150, Folder 1811)
  - Unlabeled Notes (Box 150, Folder 1812)
  - Unlabeled Notes (Box 150, Folder 1813)
  - Unlabeled Notes, "(90)1.1-(90)2.16" (Box 150, Folder 1814)
  - Unlabeled Notes, "(90)2.17-(90)4.21" (Box 150, Folder 1815)
  - Unlabeled Notes, "(90)4.22-(90)11.5" (Box 151, Folder 1816)
  - Unlabeled Notes, 1957-1958 (Box 151, Folder 1817)
  - Unlabeled Notes, 1963-1964 (Box 151, Folder 1818)
  - Unlabeled Notes, 1969 (Box 151, Folder 1819)
  - Unlabeled Notes, 1973 (Box 151, Folder 1820)
  - Unlabeled Notes, 1988 (Box 151, Folder 1821)
  - Unlabeled Notes, 1989 (Box 151, Folder 1822)
  - Unlabeled Notes, 1989 (Box 151, Folder 1823)
  - Unlabeled Notes, 1989 (Box 151, Folder 1824)
  - Unlabeled Notes, 1989 (Box 151, Folder 1825)
  - Unlabeled Notes, 1993 (Box 151, Folder 1826)
  - Unlabeled Notes and "Kurt Gödel's Intellectual Development", 1976 (Box 151, Folder 1827)
  - Unlabeled Notes and Manuscripts (Box 151, Folder 1828)
  - Unlabeled Notes and Manuscripts, Includes: “What is Logic?” “Gödel and Wittgenstein” “The Skeleton in Frege’s Cupboard: The Standard Versus Nonstandard Distinction” (Box 151, Folder 1829)
  - Unlabeled Notes, Chapter 11 (Box 151, Folder 1830)
  - Unlabeled Notes, Conversations with Kurt Gödel (Box 151, Folder 1831)
  - Unlabeled Notes, Material on Gödel, 1990-1995 (Box 152, Folder 1832)
  - Unlabeled Notes, Philosophy - Chinese and Western/East and West (Box 152, Folder 1833)
  - Unlabeled Notes, Recursive Functions, 1954 (Box 152, Folder 1834)
  - Unlabeled Notes, September 1983 (Box 152, Folder 1835)
  - "An Unsolveable Problem on Dominoes" (Box 152, Folder 1836)
  - "An Unsolvable Problem on Dominoes" and "Popular Lectures on Mathematical Logic, Postscript" by Hao Wang (Box 152, Folder 1837)
  - Untitled Manuscript, pgs. 1-242 (Box 152, Folder 1838)
  - "Varieties of Mathematical Realism - In Quest of Convergence" (Box 152, Folder 1839)
  - "A Visit to Hungarian Mathematics" by Reuben Hersh and Vera John-Steiner (Box 152, Folder 1840)
  - VMR - "Varieties of Mathematical Realism" (Box 152, Folder 1841)
  - John von Neumann (Box 152, Folder 1842)
  - Georg Henrik von Wright (Box 153, Folder 1843)
  - Wang, Unlabeled Notes (Box 153, Folder 1844)
  - Shih-Chiang Wang (Box 153, Folder 1845)
  - "Western Philosophy and China" [in Chinese] (Box 153, Folder 1846)
  - Eduard Wette (Box 153, Folder 1847)
  - "What is Logic?" (Box 153, Folder 1848)
  - "What is Logic?" (Box 153, Folder 1849)
  - M.W. Wilkes (Box 153, Folder 1850)
  - Wittgenstein, 1958 (Box 153, Folder 1851)
  - "Wittgenstein and the Twentieth Century" by Georg Henrik von Wright (Box 153, Folder 1852)
  - "Wittgenstein: Chronological Table" (Box 153, Folder 1853)
  - "Wittgenstein's and Other Mathematical Philosophies" (Box 153, Folder 1854)
  - WLP, "To Will Businesslike Perspicuity through Logic" (Box 153, Folder 1855)
  - WLP2, Includes: “Can Minds Do More than Brains?” “Mind Brain Machine” “Mind, Matter, Concept” “Some Philosophical Implications of Mathematical Logic” by John Myhill (Box 154, Folder 1856)
  - "Words in the History of a Turing Machine with a Fixed Input" (Box 154, Folder 1857)
  - WP, "To Will Only Perspicuity" (Box 154, Folder 1858)
  - Yu. I. Yanov (Box 154, Folder 1859)
  - "ZFJ and the Consistency Problem for NF" by M. Boffa (Box 154, Folder 1860)
- Reprints, 4
  - "Alternative Proof of a Theorem of Kleene" by Wang (Box 154, Folder 1861)
  - “Applications of Formalized Consistency Proofs II” by Kreisel and Wang (Box 154, Folder 1862)
  - “Arithmetic models for Formal Systems” by Wang (Box 154, Folder 1863)
  - “Arithmetic Translations of Axiom Systems” by Wang (Box 154, Folder 1864)
  - “The Axiomatization of Arithmetic” by Wang (Box 154, Folder 1865)
  - “Between Number Theory and Set Theory” by Wang (Box 154, Folder 1866)
  - “The Calculus of Partial Predicates and Its Extension to Set Theory I” by Wang (Box 154, Folder 1867)
  - “The Categoricity Question of Certain Grand Logics” by Wang (Box 154, Folder 1868)
  - “Certain Predicates Defined by Induction Schemata” by Wang (Box 154, Folder 1869)
  - “Characterizations of Ordinal Numbers in Set Theory” by Cook and Wang (Box 154, Folder 1870)
  - “China Today and Its Development over the Last Sixty Years” by Wang [in Chinese] (Box 154, Folder 1871)
  - “Circuit Synthesis by Solving Sequential Boolean Equations” by Wang (Box 154, Folder 1872)
  - “Classification of AEA Formulas by Letter Atoms” by Dreben, Kahr, and Wang (Box 154, Folder 1873)
  - “Computer Theorem Proving and Artificial Intelligence” by Wang (Box 154, Folder 1874)
  - “Concerning the Materialist Dialectic” by Wang (Box 154, Folder 1875)
  - “Dialectics and Natural Science” by Wang (Box 154, Folder 1876)
  - “Dominoes and the AEA Case of the Decision Problem” by Wang (Box 154, Folder 1877)
  - “Eighty Years of Foundational Studies” by Wang (Box 154, Folder 1878)
  - “Entscheidungsproblem Reduced to the ∀∃∀ Case” by Kahr, Moore, and Wang (Box 154, Folder 1879)
  - “Existence of Classes and Value Specification of Variables” by Wang (Box 154, Folder 1880)
  - “The Existence of Material Objects” by Wang (Box 154, Folder 1881)
  - “Existence of Nonmitotic α-Recursively Enumerable Sets” by Yang Dong-ping (Box 154, Folder 1882)
  - “Finite Set Theory, Number Theory and Axioms of Limitation” by Brown and Wang (Box 154, Folder 1883)
  - “The Formal and the Intuitive in the Biological Sciences” by Wang (Box 154, Folder 1884)
  - “A Formal System of Logic” by Wang (Box 154, Folder 1885)
  - “Formalization and Automatic Theorem-Proving” by Wang (Box 154, Folder 1886)
  - “The Formalization of Mathematics” by Wang (Box 154, Folder 1887)
  - “Games, Logic and Computers” by Wang (Box 154, Folder 1888)
  - “The Irreducibility of Impredicative Principles” by Wang (Box 154, Folder 1889)
  - “K. Gödel and L. Wittgenstein” by Wang [in Chinese] (Box 154, Folder 1890)
  - “Kurt Gödel” by Wang (Box 155, Folder 1891)
  - “Kurt Gödel’s Intellectual Development” by Wang (Box 155, Folder 1892)
  - “Kurt Gödel’s Intellectual Development” by Wang (Box 155, Folder 1893)
  - “Language and Metaphysics” by Wang [in Chinese] (Box 155, Folder 1894)
  - “Large Sets” by Wang (Box 155, Folder 1895)
  - “Les Systèmes Axiomatiques de la Théorie des Ensembles” by Wang (Box 155, Folder 1896)
  - Letters to the Editor, by Wang, 1971-1976 (Box 155, Folder 1897)
  - “Logic and Computers” by Wang (Box 155, Folder 1898)
  - “Logic, Computation and Philosophy” by Wang (Box 154, Folder 1899)
  - “Logic for the Computer Sciences – Critique” by Wang (Box 154, Folder 1900)
  - “The Logic of Automata” by Burks and Wang (Box 154, Folder 1901)
  - “Logic of Many-Sorted Theories” by Wang (Box 154, Folder 1902)
  - “Mathematical Logic” by Wang [in Chinese] (Box 154, Folder 1903)
  - “Mechanical Mathematics and Inferential Analysis” by Wang (Box 154, Folder 1904)
  - not assigned (Box 154, Folder 1905)
  - “Mechanical Treatment of Chinese Characters” by Wang [in Chinese] (Box 154, Folder 1906)
  - “The Mechanization of Mathematical Arguments” by Wang (Box 154, Folder 1907)
  - “Memories Related to Professor Y.L. Chin” by Wang [in Chinese] (Box 154, Folder 1908)
  - “Metalogic” by Wang (Box 154, Folder 1909)
  - “Natural Hulls and Set Existence” by Wang (Box 154, Folder 1910)
  - “Negative Types” by Wang (Box 154, Folder 1911)
  - “New Hopes and Old Fears” by Wang (Box 154, Folder 1912)
  - “A New Theory of Element and Number” by Wang (Box 154, Folder 1913)
  - “The Non-Finitizability of Impredicative Principles” by Wang (Box 154, Folder 1914)
  - “Non-Standard Models for Formal Logic” by Rosser and Wang (Box 154, Folder 1915)
  - “A Note on Quine’s Principles of Quantification” by Wang (Box 154, Folder 1916)
  - “Note on the Rules of Inference” by Wang (Box 154, Folder 1917)
  - “Notes on a Class of Tiling Problems” by Wang (Box 154, Folder 1918)
  - “Notes on the Analytic-Synthetic Distinction” by Wang (Box 154, Folder 1919)
  - “Notes on the Analytic-Synthetic Distinction” by Wang [in Chinese] (Box 154, Folder 1920)
  - “Notes on the Justification of Induction” by Wang (Box 155, Folder 1921)
  - “Number Theoretic Concepts and Recursive Well-Ordering” by Wang (Box 155, Folder 1922)
  - “On Axioms of Conditional Set Existence” by Wang (Box 155, Folder 1923)
  - “On Denumerable Bases of Formal Systems” by Wang (Box 155, Folder 1924)
  - “On Formalization” by Wang (Box 155, Folder 1925)
  - “On Ordinals” by Quine and Wang (Box 155, Folder 1926)
  - “On Scepticism About Induction” by Wang (Box 155, Folder 1927)
  - “On the Long-Range Prospects of Automatic Theorem-Proving” by Wang (Box 155, Folder 1928)
  - “On Zermelo’s and von Neumann’s Axioms for Set Theory” by Wang (Box 155, Folder 1929)
  - “Ordinal Numbers and Predicative Set Theory” by Wang (Box 155, Folder 1930)
  - “A Philosophical Look at Intuition” by Wang (Box 155, Folder 1931)
  - “Philosophy: Chinese and Western” by Wang (Box 155, Folder 1932)
  - “Process and Existence in Mathematics” by Wang (Box 155, Folder 1933)
  - “Process and Existence in Mathematics” by Wang [in Russian] (Box 155, Folder 1934)
  - “A Proof of Independence” by Wang (Box 155, Folder 1935)
  - “Proving Theorems by Pattern Recognition I” by Wang (Box 155, Folder 1936)
  - “Proving Theorems by Pattern Recognition II” by Wang (Box 155, Folder 1937)
  - “Quelques Notions d’Axiomatique” by Wang (Box 155, Folder 1938)
  - “A Question of Knowledge” by Wang (Box 155, Folder 1939)
  - “A Recipe for Chinese Typewriters” by Wang [in Chinese] (Box 155, Folder 1940)
  - “Reflections on a Visit to China” by Wang [in Chinese] (Box 155, Folder 1941)
  - “Remarks on Machines, Sets, and the Decision Problem” by Wang (Box 155, Folder 1942)
  - “Remarks on Mathematics and Computers” by Wang (Box 155, Folder 1943)
  - “Remarks on the Comparison of Axiom Systems” by Wang (Box 155, Folder 1944)
  - “Remeeting Mr. Shen Tsung-wen” by Wang [in Chinese] (Box 155, Folder 1945)
  - Reprint Requests (Box 156, Folder 1946)
  - “Russell and His Logic” by Wang (Box 156, Folder 1947)
  - “Russell and Philosophy” by Wang (Box 156, Folder 1948)
  - “Russell und Seine Logik” by Wang [in German] (Box 156, Folder 1949)
  - “Russell y su Lógica” by Wang [in Spanish] (Box 156, Folder 1950)
  - “The Searchings of Lu Hsun” by Wang [in Chinese] (Box 156, Folder 1951)
  - “Set-Theoretical Basis for Real Numbers” by Wang (Box 156, Folder 1952)
  - “Short Definitions of the Ordinals” by Brown and Wang (Box 156, Folder 1953)
  - “Some Applications of Formalized Consistency Proofs” by Kreisel and Wang (Box 156, Folder 1954)
  - “Some Facts about Kurt Gödel” by Wang (Box 156, Folder 1955)
  - “Sprecker’s Mathematical Work from 1949 to 1979” by Wang (Box 156, Folder 1956)
  - “A Survey of Skolem’s Work in Logic” by Wang (Box 156, Folder 1957)
  - “Tag Systems and Lag Systems” by Wang (Box 156, Folder 1958)
  - “A Theorem on Definitions of the Zermelo-Neumann Ordinals” (Box 156, Folder 1959)
  - “A Theory of Constructive Types” by Wang (Box 156, Folder 1960)
  - “To Confirm some Impressions by Lu Xun” by Wang [in Chinese] (Box 156, Folder 1961)
  - “Toward Mechanical Mathematics” by Wang (Box 156, Folder 1962)
  - “Towards Feasible Solutions of the Tautology Problem” by Dunham and Wang (Box 156, Folder 1963)
  - “Truth Definitions and Consistency Proofs” by Wang (Box 156, Folder 1964)
  - “Undecidable Sentences Generated by Semantic Paradoxes” by Wang (Box 156, Folder 1965)
  - “Universal Turing Machines: An Exercise in Coding” by Wang (Box 156, Folder 1966)
  - “A Variant to Turing’s Theory of Computing Machines” by Wang (Box 156, Folder 1967)
  - “Was ist ein Individuum?” by Wang (Box 156, Folder 1968)
  - “What is an Individual?” by Wang (Box 156, Folder 1969)
  - “Wittgenstein’s and Other Mathematical Philosophies” by Wang (Box 156, Folder 1970)
  - “Words in the History of a Turing Machines with a Fixed Input” by Rabin and Wang (Box 156, Folder 1971)